travisa.com 2018-08-16

# Travisa Privacy Policy

Travisa and parent company CIBT (hereinafter referred to as “CIBT”) is committed to providing exceptional customer service. As part of this commitment, we take the trust our customers and site visitors place in us very seriously. We recognize that it is our responsibility to protect your privacy and to inform you of our information and data collection practices through our Privacy Policy. 

The following describes what information is collected and explains how that information may be used, how we secure the personal information you provide, and the instances in which we may share that information with third parties. It also describes your choices regarding use, access and correction of your personal information. By visiting this website you are accepting and consenting to Travisa’s collection and use of personal data as described in this Privacy Policy. 

Furthermore, Travisa complies with the EU-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework and Swiss-U.S. Privacy Shield Framework as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use, and retention of personal information transferred from the European Union and Switzerland to the United States. Travisa has certified to the Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Privacy Shield Principles. If there is any conflict between the terms in this Privacy Policy and the Privacy Shield Principles, the Privacy Shield Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Privacy Shield, and to view our certification, please visit [https://www.privacyshield.gov](https://www.privacyshield.gov/). 

Travisa is committed to complying with the Privacy Shield Principles covering all personal data received from the EU and Switzerland. 

##  The Information We Collect 

By using our websites and services we may collect and request from you including your name, title, company, address, telephone number and e-mail address. If Travisa is handling your visa or immigration matter, then the information you provide may include your personal and family information, educational background, health, and employment history. We also collect information with regard to each of your visits to our website which is stored in log files. 

##  How Information Is Used 

We do not sell your personal information to third parties. Additionally, Travisa will not share the information with any third party, except as otherwise set forth in this Privacy Policy. 

Travisa may share the following information with third parties: 

  * To complete your visa, document legalization, or immigration support request as necessary to provide visa and immigration services to you and your family, including disclosure to government agencies in the form of applications, photographs, and petitions for visa request and/or immigration benefits 
  * To companies that provide services to assist us with our business activities in visa and immigration request fulfillment 
  * To improve our products and services, provide superior customer service, and identify market opportunities 
  * As required by law in response to requests by public authorities including meeting national security or law enforcement requirements 

Travisa may also use the information to communicate with you directly via survey, e-mail or direct mail, such as to inform you about newsworthy topics and upcoming events that may be of interest to you, or to confer with you regarding your visa or passport request, or immigration case. We may also use your email address to send you reminders of expiring visas, passports, or immigration status. If you would like to discontinue receiving this information see the Choice/Opt-out section below. 

##  Accountability for Onward Transfer 

In the event Travisa transfers personal data covered by this Privacy Policy to a third party acting as a controller, Travisa will do so consistent with any notice provided to the subjects of that data and any consent they have given, and only if the third party has given Travisa contractual assurances that it will (i) process the personal data for limited and specified purposes consistent with any consent provided by the subjects of such data; (ii) provide at least the same level of protection as is required by the Privacy Shield Principles and notify us if it makes a determination that it cannot do so; and (iii) cease processing of the personal data or take other reasonable and appropriate steps to remediate if it makes such a determination. If Travisa has knowledge that a third party acting as a controller is processing personal data covered by this Privacy Policy in a way that is contrary to the Privacy Shield Principles, Travisa will take reasonable steps to prevent or stop such processing. 

With respect to Travisa’s agents, Travisa will only transfer the personal data covered by this Privacy Policy needed for an agent to deliver to Travisa the requested product or service. In addition, Travisa will (i) permit the agent to process such personal data only for limited and specified purposes; (ii) require the agent to provide at least the same level of privacy protection as is required by the Privacy Shield Principles; (iii) take reasonable and appropriate steps to ensure that the agent effectively processes the Personal Data transferred in a manner consistent with Travisa’s obligations under the Privacy Shield Principles; and (iv) require the agent to notify Travisa if it makes a determination that it can no longer meet its obligation to provide the same level of protection as is required by the Privacy Shied Principles. Upon receiving notice from an agent that it can no longer meet its obligation to provide the same level of protection as is required by the Privacy Shield Principles, Travisa will take reasonable and appropriate steps to stop and remediate unauthorized processing. 

Travisa remains liable under the Privacy Shield Principles if an agent processes personal data covered by this Privacy Policy in a manner inconsistent with the Privacy Shield Principles, except where Travisa is not responsible for the event giving rise to the damage. 

If Travisa transfers personal data to one of its affiliated entities within its corporate group, Travisa will take steps to ensure that such personal data is protected within the same level of protection that the Privacy Shield Principles require. 

##  Protecting Your Information 

Protecting personal information we receive from you is of crucial importance to Travisa While there is always some risk involved with transmitting information over the internet, we strive to protect against the misuse of any personal information that we receive from you via our website. To guard your nonpublic personal information, we maintain physical, electronic and procedural safeguards. Travisa data is protected by Secure Socket Layer (SSL) technology. This technology ensures the safe transmission of all data, including personal and credit card information. By taking such measures, Travisa customers can feel secure in the knowledge that their data is protected when using our website. 

We generally delete personal data within 90 days after our services conclude; however, we will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, government auditing requirements, resolve disputes, and enforce our agreements. At the end of such period, we may, at our discretion, destroy such personal data without notice to you. 

##  Cookies/Online Tracking 

Travisa uses cookies to enhance your experience while using our website. Cookies are identifiers conveyed to your computer's hard drive enabling our systems to recognize your browser. Cookies allow us to communicate certain information or content particular to your needs and interests. Our site also uses cookies to anonymously track movement within our site. 

Travisa employs third-party entities to perform functions on our behalf such as data analysis and marketing assistance. The data that we provide them is anonymous and does not reveal specific personal information related to our customers. This data is used for specific functions that require broad-based user statistics which help to improve the overall Travisa customer experience. You can disable cookies on your computer. Should you do so, helpful information may be omitted from your service experience. In addition, we do not respond to web browser 'do not track' signals however we will continue to monitor relevant legislation and policy updates and adjust our ‘do not track’ strategy as required. 

##  Links to Other Websites 

The website includes links to other websites whose privacy practices may differ from those of Travisa If you submit personal information to any of those websites, your information is governed by their privacy statements. We encourage you to carefully read the privacy statement of any website you visit. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of others. Any link to a website owned by a third party does not constitute an endorsement, approval, association, sponsorship or affiliation with the linked site unless specifically stated. 

The website includes social media features, such as the Facebook Like button and widgets, such as the Share this button or interactive mini-programs that run on the website. These features may collect your IP address, which page you are visiting on the website, and may set a cookie to enable the feature to function properly. Social media features and widgets are either hosted by a third party or hosted directly on the website. Your interactions with these features are governed by the privacy policy of the company providing it. 

##  Choice/Opt-Out 

We provide users the opportunity to opt-out of receiving further communications from us at their request. Users may also opt-out of any disclosure of their personal data by Travisa to independent third parties (except as is necessary for Travisa to provide any services requested by the user or as required by law), or use of personal data that is materially different from the purpose for which it was originally collected. Please use the opt-out features on the email communications you receive from us or contact us using the Contacting Us information posted at the bottom of this webpage. 

##  Accessing or Updating Personally Identifiable Information 

Upon request Travisa will provide you with information about whether we hold any of your personal information. If your personally identifiable information changes, or if you no longer desire our service, you may correct, update, or amend it by emailing or contacting us by telephone or postal mail at the contact information listed below. We will respond to your request within a reasonable timeframe. 

##  Changes to This Privacy Policy 

Any changes to this Privacy Policy will be made through a revised posting on the website. 

##  Recourse, Enforcement and Liability 

Travisa has mechanisms in place designed to help assure compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles. Travisa conducts an annual self-assessment of its consumer personal data practices to verify that the attestations and assertions the company makes about its Privacy Shield privacy practices are true and that the company’s privacy practices have been implemented as represented and in accordance with the Privacy Shield Principles. 

Consumers may file a complaint concerning Travisa’s processing of their Personal Data. Travisa will take steps to remedy issues arising out of its alleged failure to comply with the Privacy Shield Principles. Consumers may contact Travisa as specified below about complaints regarding the company’s Consumer Personal Data practices. 

If a Consumer’s complaint cannot be resolved through Travisa’s internal processes, Travisa will cooperate with JAMS pursuant to the JAMS International Mediation Rules, available on the JAMS website at https://www.jamsadr.com/eu-us-privacy-shield. JAMS mediation may be commenced as provided for in the relevant JAMS rules. Following the dispute resolution process, JAMS or the Consumer may refer the matter to the U.S. Federal Trade Commission, which has Privacy Shield investigatory and enforcement powers over Travisa Under certain circumstances, Consumers also may be able to invoke binding arbitration to address complaints about Travisa’s compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles. 

Travisa’s compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles is subject to the investigatory and enforcement powers of the Federal Trade Commission. 

##  Contacting Us 

In compliance with the Privacy Shield Principles, Travisa commits to resolve complaints about our collection or use of your personal information. EU and Swiss individuals with inquires or complaints regarding our Privacy Policy and our adherence to the Privacy Shield Principles should first contact Travisa at: 

**Privacy Policy Team**  
1600 International Drive, Suite 600  
McLean, VA 22102  
703-903-1400 

Travisa has further committed to cooperate with the panel established by the EU data protection authorities (DPAs) and the Swiss Federal Data Protection and Information Commissioner (FDPIC) with regard to unresolved Privacy Shield complaints concerning data transferred from the EU and Switzerland. 

##  Disclaimer 

While every effort is made to provide accurate information, visa, passport, legalization, and immigration requirements are constantly changing and there may be a delay before we are advised of such changes. Therefore, we are unable to guarantee complete accuracy at all times. Processing times and fees given are solely for guidance purposes and cannot be guaranteed. Where ‘no’ visa is indicated, we recommend this information be confirmed by the carrier and the relevant embassy or consulate. Travisa recommends that visas be obtained before travel. Where information for visas upon arrival are given, we always recommend confirmation of this information with the airline and embassy or high commission prior to travel. Travel arrangements should not be confirmed prior to the visa or passport being issued, unless they are a specifically required for that consulate. In such cases, refundable arrangements should be made. 

If you purchase services from our site, our terms and conditions of supply Terms of Use will apply to the sales.
